Guide to the Timothy Lester Woodruff Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Timothy Lester Woodruff family papers
1776-1904
MS 1229
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
Family correspondence of John Woodruff and his son, Timothy Lester Woodruff. Included are several items documenting John Woodruff's career as a Congressman from Connecticut (1855-1857; 1859-1861) and his election on the American Party ticket. Also in the papers is a letter from Samuel Scott, an ancestor of the family, written while serving in the American Revolution.
Woodruff, Timothy L. (Timothy Lester), 1858-1913
Existence and Location of Copies
Correspondence, memorabilia, and clippings of Timothy L. Woodruff are available on microfilm (11,643 frames on 13 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM 86.
Biographical / Historical
John Woodruff: member of Common Council of New Haven, Ct., from 1848; member Connecticut General Assembly, 1852; member of Congress, 1855-1857, 1859-1861; Collector of Internal Revenue for Connecticut, 1862-1868.
Timothy L. Woodruff: president Maltine Manufacturing Co. and Pneumelectric Machine Co., Syracuse; lieutenant-governor of New York, 1897-1903.
Scope and Contents
Family correspondence of John Woodruff and his son, Timothy Lester Woodruff. Included are several items documenting John Woodruff's career as a Congressman from Connecticut (1855-1857; 1859-1861) and his election on the American Party ticket. Also in the papers is a letter from Samuel Scott, an ancestor of the family, written while serving in the American Revolution.
Appendix: Microfilm inventory
HM 86 - Scrapbooks. Correspondence, memorabilia and clippings relating to T.L. Woodruff, his activities in the Republican Party and as lieutenant governor of New York, 1897-1903.
Microfilm. New Haven, Yale University Library, 1979. 13 reels / 65 v. [Vol. 48 is missing].
Note: Numbers listed in the Folder column indicate volumes.
1847 Sep 28- 1897 Apr 21 1 1-4
1897 Apr 21 - 1898 May 31 2 4-8
1898 Jun 1 - 1899 Sep 17 3 8-13
1899 Sep 17 - 1900 Jun 20 4 14-18
1900 Jun 20 - 1901 Aug 25 5 19-23
1901 Aug 25 - 1902 Sep 10 6 24-28
1902 Sep 10 - 1903 Dec 17 7 29-33
1903 Dec 17 - 1905 Dec 27 8 34-39
1905 Dec 27 - 1907 Jul 3 9 40-45
1907 Jul 5 - 1907 Dec 17 10 46-47
1908 Mar 4 - 1908 Dec 3 10 49-52
1908 Dec 3 - 1910 Jul 6 11 53-58
1910 Jul 6 - 1912 Jun 5 12 59-63
1912 Jun 5 - 1913 Oct 20 13 64-66
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Families; Connecticut -- Politics and government; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government; New York (State) -- Politics and government; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- Politics and government; Legislators; Politicians; Woodruff, John, 1826-1868; Woodruff, Timothy L. (Timothy Lester), 1858-1913; Woodruff family; American Party -- Connecticut; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1879
- Inventory, 1776, 1849-1904, undated; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Scott, Samuel (active 1776)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to his wife, Lois Scott, 1776 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Genealogy and copy of Lois Scott's reply, 1776 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      See also: box 1, folder 7
  - Woodruff, Jane (Lester) (Mrs. John)
    - Correspondence, 1856-1863 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Genealogy of the Lester family, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodruff, John (1826-1868)
    - Correspondence, 1849-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Financial papers, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Political papers - Campaign handbill, [1854] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript, speech for re-election, [1860?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Memorabilia and clippings, 1847-1857, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Woodruff, Timothy Lester (1858-1913)
    - Correspondence, 1879-1892 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Genealogy, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "The Rise of Spartan Power", 1874 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Address to the Hardware Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mementos of the Republican National Convention, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Campaign posters, 1898, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mementos of the visit of H. R. H. Prince Henry of Prussia, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 11)